[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Good afternoon, I'm Jason
&gt;&gt; 下午好 我叫 Jason Morley
Morley, a software engineer on
是 Apple Health 团队的
the Health Team here at Apple.
一名软件工程师
And along with my colleague
这是我的同事 Peyton
Peyton I'd like to take some
我想花些时间
time to introduce you to an
来向你们介绍
exciting new feature we have in
我们今年在 iOS 12 里加入的
iOS 12 this year, access to
一项激动人心的新功能
health records with HealthKit.
利用 HealthKit 获得健康记录
Earlier this year in iOS 11.3 we
在今年的早些时候
introduced Health Records and
我们在 iOS 11.3 上介绍了 健康记录和健康
Users can connect to their
用户可以与他们的
healthcare institutions and
医疗机构建立连接
securely download their health
并且安全地下载他们的健康记录
records for quick access and
以便于快速访问和保管
We aggregate data from multiple
我们从多个医疗机构那里
healthcare institutions and
收集数据并且
present it in a timeline
呈现一个允许用户搜索和
allowing users to search and
显示像实验值和参考范围这种
surfacing important details like
真的能够帮助用户
lab values and reference ranges
去更好地了解
really helping users to better
他们健康数据的重要细节
understand their health data.
的时间轴
As of today we have support for
截止至今 我们已经为
more than 500 US hospitals and
超过 500 家美国医院和诊所
clinics covering over 50
提供了支持 共覆盖 50 多个医疗机构
healthcare institutions and we
并且我们还在不断地
are continuing to add more.
继续增加更多
Of course this wouldn't be
当然了
possible without the fantastic
如果没有
standards work of the Health
Health Level Seven 组织
Level Seven organization with
的杰出劳动
their fast healthcare
和他们的快速医疗的交互操作能力
interoperability resources or
或 FHIR 和智能健康 IT 项目
FHIR and the Smart health IT
的帮助的话
project.
这将是不可能实现的
For us it all starts with
对我们来说
health, we establish a secure
这一切都是从健康出发
connection to healthcare
我们和医疗机构建立了一个
institutions and download users'
安全的连接
health records in FHIR direct to
并从 FHIR 直接将用户的健康记录
their iOS devices.
下载到他们的 iOS 装置上
From here we it store securely
从这里我们将它安全地
in HealthKit and aggregate data
储存在 HealthKit 上
across multiple institutions.
并跨越多个机构汇总数据
Starting today in iOS 12 we are
从现如今的 iOS 12 开始
providing APIs to allow you to
我们提供允许你访问这个数据的 API
access this data and work with
并且让你能够
it in your apps.
在你的 App 中使用它
First, I'm going to introduce
首先 我来介绍一下
the new sample types that we've
我们新加的用来支持这个功能的
added to support this feature.
新的样本类型
Then we can see how you
然后 我们便能够看到
authorize your application and
你是如何授权自己的 App 并且
query for data.
查询数据的
After that, I'll take a brief
然后 我将简短介绍一下 FHIR
dive into FHIR and show you
并且向你们展示
what's possible here.
一下它有多少种可能性
And finally, we can take some
最后 我们可以花些时间
time to think about how you can
来思考一下
help protect your users' privacy
在这个敏感的领域
in this sensitive domain.
你该如何保护你的用户隐私
So let's jump right in.
好了让我们进入正题
If you've used HealthKit before
如果你之前使用过 HealthKit 的话
you may be familiar with
你可能会对 HKSampleType 和它的子类很熟悉
These group similar types of
它们是像分组一样的数据
data, for example QuantityType
例如 QuantityType 这种
groups data represented by a
由一个单一数值代表
single numerical value, things
的分组数据
like step count and heart rate.
像步数和心率
While CategoryType groups data
然而 CategoryType 分组数据
characterized by enumeration,
是以枚举来判断其特征的
things like sleep analysis, am I
像睡眠分析这种
in bed or asleep or menstrual
我只是躺在床上 还是睡着了
flow, heavy or light.
我的月经流量如何等
And to support Health Records
并且 为了支持健康记录
we're introducing HKClinicalType
我们引入能够将
which groups the categories of
你在 Health 中看到的
health records that you see in
像状态和药方这种
Health, things like conditions
健康记录分类的
and medications.
HKClinicalType
Within each of these sample
在每个样本类型中
types the different data types
不同的数据类型
are differentiated by a type
由一个类型识别码来进行区分
HKClinicalType identifier
HKClinicalType 识别码
identifies the clinical types
通过相应的
that correspond with the
健康记录和健康的类别来识别
Health.
相应的临床类型
We have allergies, conditions,
我们会有过敏等一些
these might be short-term
可能仅仅是短期才会出现的状况
conditions such as pregnancy or
例如怀孕
ongoing conditions like type II
或者是一些经常性的状况
diabetes, immunizations, lab
比如第二类型糖尿病 免疫接种 实验结果
results, these might be my blood
这些可能是为了
glucose measurement for my
我每年的身体检查
annual physical.
而进行的血糖测量
Medications, procedures, a
药物 流程
diagnostic procedure or a
诊断过程或是手术
And vital signs, things like
生命体征中像这种
blood pressure or weight.
血压或体重的测量
Alongside these sample types and
除了这些样本类型和
sample type identifiers, we're
样本类型标识符以外
also introducing a new HK sample
我们还引入一个叫做 HKClinicalRecord 的
subclass HKClinicalRecord.
新的 HK 样本子类
If you're not familiar with
如果你对于
working with samples in
在 HealthKit 中操作这些样本
HealthKit we have a number of
并不熟悉
talks that cover this topic and
我们可以深入探讨这个话题
I'll provide details of these at
并且我将在最后介绍
the end.
一些关于它的细节
There are a few key properties
如果你打算使用 HKClinicalRecord 的话
you'll be working with on
那么 这里有一些
HKClinicalRecord.
你需要了解的关键属性
The clinical type, we looked at
关于临床类型
this earlier and this allows you
我们之前也探讨过
to determine the type of a given
它允许你去确定
record.
一个记录的类型
I want to know that a health
健康记录
record is for example an
就像免疫接种一样
We provide a display name which
我们提供了一个名字
is a string that we use when
它是一个我们在 Health 中
showing that health record to
用来向用户展示健康记录的
users in Health.
一个字符串
It's selected from the FHIR
我们从 FHIR 资源中把它选择出来
resource and it's your
并且你能够将
opportunity to tie back your
你的 App 之前的经历
app's experience to something
与用户所熟悉的东西
users are familiar with.
绑定在一起
You can see in this lab result
你可以从这个实验结果中看到
that there are a number of
有许多可选择的
alternative representations and
表示方法和名称
names, including a coding in the
包括 LOINC 编码系统里的
LOINC coding system.
一个编码
This is an industry standard
这是一个医疗信息界的
reference for medical
行业标准化参考
information and it is required
并且它是 FHIR
by FHIR for observations.
进行观测所需要的
You can see here that we've
从这里你可以看到
taken that LOINC coding and
我们已经采用 LOINC 编码并且
performed a lookup to provide a
执行了一个查找去
canonical name which we will
提供一个我们将为你们
surface to you as the display
呈现的一个规范名称
And finally, we provide access
最终 我们提供完整的
to the full FHIR resource, but
FHIR 资源的访问端口
there's a lot you can benefit
但是从 HKClinicalRecord 中
from looking at the
你还可以得到很多益处
HKClinicalRecord so I'm going to
所以我现在
set this aside right now and we
先把它放在一边
can come back to it later.
稍后我们再回来讨论
Like all of Health data,
像所有的健康数据一样
provenance, or the source of
数据的来源
that data, is very important.
是非常重要的
You want to know where this
你想要知道这个健康数据
health record comes from.
是从哪里来的
And as with the rest of
并且和 HealthKit 的其他部分一样
HealthKit we model this using
我们使用 HKSample 的超类 HKSource
HKSource which is available on
来对其进行建模
We set the name to be the name
我们将名称设置为
of the healthcare institution
医疗机构
that they have shared with us
跟我们分享的名称
and we provide a bundle
并且我们提供了一个
identifier which is a stable
包标识符 它是一个能够
identifier for that healthcare
使该医疗机构实现
institution across multiple user
跨多个用户和多个设备登录的
logins and devices.
稳定的标识符
So now we've seen the new sample
所以现在
types.
我们已经看到了这个新的样本类型
Let's see how you authorize your
让我们来看看 你如何授权 App
application and query for data.
并查找数据的吧
As you can see, there's a huge
可以看到 这里有个装有丰富的
wealth of information in medical
医疗记录的庞大信息库
records and we really believe
并且我们认为
that that is a fantastic
这对你来说
opportunity for you to provide
是一个能够为你的用户提供
your users with truly empowering
关于他们的健康数据的
experiences around their health
绝佳体验的
data.
千载难逢的机会
But of course health records
但是当然了
also contain incredibly
健康记录也含有
sensitive information.
令人难以置信的敏感信息
A user's health records might
用户的健康记录或许会
contain details of medications
包含着他们正在服用的
that they are taking or
药物的详细信息
conditions that they are living
或者是他们每天的基本生活
with on a daily basis.
伴随着的一些状况
This is information they may not
这可能是他们
be comfortable sharing with a
不愿意与他们亲近的朋友或家人
close friend or family member.
所分享的信息
And it can change over time as a
并且伴随着用户和医疗机构
user interacts with their
之间的交流 这种情况
healthcare institution, they
会随着时间的推移而发生变化
might receive a new diagnosis of
他们或许会得到
a condition.
关于这个状况的新的诊断
So to help our users better
所以 为了能够更好地帮助我们的用户
understand and manage access to
去理解和管理这些数据的
that data we're introducing a
访问 我们引入了
new authorization flow specific
一个具体针对健康记录的授权流程
When your app requests
当你的 App 申请授权时
authorization we will present a
我们会提供一个
new permission sheet specific to
新的针对特定临床类型的许可表
First, we inform users what it
首先 我们告知用户
means to share that data with
在 App 上分享数据意味着什么
your app and just how sensitive
并且告知用户
it is.
它有多么敏感
Since we will present this new
因为我们要使用这个新的授权流程
authorization flow, whenever you
所以无论何时 只要你申请授权
request authorization you should
你需要保证
ensure that you time your
你的授权申请时间足够
authorization requests to make
以确保你的用户能够
sure your user has sufficient
充分地理解
context with which to understand
这个新的流程的内容
After this we allow users to
在这之后
select the types of data that
我们允许用户
they choose to share with your
从你已经提出请求的类别中
app from the categories that you
选择他们想要和你的 App
have requested.
实现共享的数据类型
We also present a new purpose
我们还提出了一个
string and your app's privacy
新的目标字符串
policy in the app explanation
和在 App 解释说明部分中的
section.
你的 App 的隐私政策
This is really your opportunity
这是一个去向用户解释
to explain to users why you need
你为什么需要去访问数据
access to that data, what you're
你将用它来做什么
going to do with it, and how you
和你将如何保护他们的数据的
will protect that data.
千载难逢的好机会
You should be sure to make sure
你一定要确保
that what you request is
你的要求和你的需要
proportional to what you need.
是成比例的
Users are really going to be
用户真的会
surprised and concerned if they
很惊讶并且担心是否
see types here that don't
他们在这里所看到的数据类型
pertain to the primary function
并不属于你的 App 的主要功能
And finally because data can
并且最终会因为
change over time as a user
用户和他们的医疗机构的互动
interacts with their healthcare
而造成数据会随着时间发生变化
institution, we're introducing a
我们正在引入一个
new way to control how new data
新的方法来控制与你的 App
is shared with your app.
共享新数据的方式
We default to asking before
我们默认会去询问
sharing new data each and every
之前每一次共享的每一个数据
This means we may need to
这意味着每当新的数据可用时
present the new permission sheet
我们可能需要
whenever new data is available.
提交新的许可表
So when you need to query for
所以每当你需要查询数据的时候
data you should always request
你都应该去
authorization prior to doing so.
申请相应的权限
Okay, so how do I get started
好 那么我该怎样开始
and request authorization?
并且请求权限呢
This flow is going to look very
这个流程看上去
familiar to those of you who've
会让那些之前用过 HealthKit 的人
worked with HealthKit before.
觉得很熟悉
First, I need to configure the
首先 我需要配置这个项目
After that request
在进行授权请求后
And finally query for data.
最后查询数据
To configure your project you
为了配置你的项目
need to add a new health records
你需要在启动 HealthKit 以后
capability in Xcode after
在 Xcode 中
enabling HealthKit.
添加一个新的
Then you add the new Health
健康记录功能
Records Usage Description
然后你在你的 Info.plist 中
purpose string to your
添加一个新的
Info.plist.
健康记录用法说明字符串
Again, this is your opportunity
再次说明 这是你的好机会
to explain to users why you need
去向用户解释
access to this data and what you
你为什么需要得到数据
will do with it.
和你将利用它来做什么
Having done this, you can
完成上述步骤后
request authorization.
你可以请求权限了
Here I define the types I wish
我在这里定义
to access, conditions,
我希望访问的类型 状态
immunizations, and medications.
免疫接种和药物治疗
And then you can call request
然后你就可以
authorization on the Health
在健康中心中
Store.
调用授权请求
Being sure to handle any errors
请确保已经处理了所有错误
and after that you're good to
在这之后
query.
你便能够进行查找了
You should be aware that in
你应该知道
order to maintain user privacy
为了维护用户的隐私
we don't reveal to you which
我们不会向你透露
categories a user has granted
哪个分类是用户已准许访问的
access or denied access to.
或是已拒绝访问的
And now to querying.
现在 让我们来说查询
Because HKClinicalRecord is an
因为 HKClinicalRecord 是一个
HKSample you can take advantage
在 HealthKit 中
of all of the existing sample
你可以很好地利用
query infrastructure in
所有的现有样本查询基础设施的
HealthKit.
HKSample
Things like SampleQuery,
SampleQuery
AnchoredObjectQuery and
AnchoredObjectQuery 和
ObserverQuery will all work and
ObserverQuery 都将正常工作
if your user has granted
并且如果你的用户已经准许
continuous access background
后台连续访问
delivery will also work.
delivery 也将正常工作
Again, you define the type that
再次说明 你定义了
you wish to query for.
你希望查找的类型
We're creating a sample query
我们在这里正在创建一个查找示例
here and you can execute that on
并且你可以在健康中心执行它
So that's the basic
以上就是最基本的
authorization flow.
授权流程
But we've actually introduced
但我们已经介绍过了
some additional mechanisms
一些针对于健康记录的
specific to Health Records.
特定的额外机制
We have a new API Get Request
对于授权 我们有一个
Status for Authorization, which
新的 API 获取请求
allows you to determine if we
它允许你去确定
would present a permission sheet
我们是否去向用户
to the user.
展示许可表
This gives you an opportunity to
这给了你一个机会去
determine whether your user will
确定你的用户是否
need to see the authorization
需要去看这个许可表
sheet and optionally present a
并且选择性地展示一个 UI
UI to provide them with more
以便在授权前给他们提供
context prior to authorization.
更多的信息
To do this you call Get Request
为了做到这一点 你可以去健康中心
Status for Authorization on the
访问授权请求状态
Health Store, handle any errors,
处理错误
and if the request status is
并且如果请求状态是
should request you can
可以请求的话 你可以
optionally present that UI prior
选择在请求权限之前
to requesting authorization.
去展示 UI
Now there may also be some types
现在 可能也会有一些
of data that your app requires
你的 App 所需要访问的
access to, to provide a safe
数据类型 来保证安全
experience or perhaps if you
又或者你如果有一个需要
have a research app you need
获得全面的一系列类型的
access to a comprehensive set of
研究型 App 来
types to avoid skewed results.
避免有误差的结果
We have a new required types key
我们在 Info.plist 中
in the Info.plist, which allows
有一个新的允许你去指定这些类型
you to specify these types.
所必需的键
And if they're present we will
并且如果用户没有准许给这些类型授权
return a new required types
可它们仍然在的话
error if the user has not
我们将返回一个
granted access to these types.
新的所需类型错误
And this allows you to determine
这能够让你确定
how to behave, optionally
如何去表现
explaining to the user that you
去选择性地去向用户解释
cannot continue if you don't
如果你没有这个数据的话
have this data.
你就不能够继续
You can implement this by adding
你可以通过在你的 Info.plist 中
the new required read
添加新的所需的
authorization key to your
阅读权限密钥
Info.plist.
来实现它
Here I'm specifying that I
在这里我说我需要
require allergies, conditions
过敏 当前状态
and immunizations.
和免疫接种的信息
And then you handle the new
然后你在
error in the authorization
授权请求中
request.
处理新的错误
You should be sure to use this
你要确保能够明智地使用它
judiciously and try not to limit
并且尽量不去限制
your app's functionality based
基于你可访问数据的
to.
App 的功能
You really want to make sure as
你真的想要确定
many users as possible can
无论你的用户想要
benefit from your app
分享多少数据
irrespective of how much data
都有尽可能多的用户
they choose to share.
能够从你的 App 中受益
So that's the full authorization
所以这是一个完整的授权流量
flow and there's just a couple
并且这里有一些
of points I'd like to focus on.
我希望去关注的点
Firstly, you should be sure to
首先 你应该确保无论何时
request authorization each and
每一次你想要访问数据
every time that you need access
你都需要去请求权限
to data, especially now because
尤其是现在
users may want to see that sheet
因为用户可能希望每次有新数据进入时
every time when new data comes
都查看这个许可表
in we may need to present a
因此我们可能 要在每次你需要查找的时候
sheet when you need to query.
去呈现这个许可表
You should also be sure to
你还应该确保
request only access to the data
这个请求只会访问
that you need.
你需要的数据
And finally, you should consider
并且最后 你应该
taking advantage of the new APIs
通过充分利用新的 API
to provide users with better
来为用户提供更好的使用环境
context and allow you to time
也为你自己
those authorization requests.
提供充足的时间来验证请求
And with that I'd like to hand
我想要把
over to my colleague Peyton to
下面的内容交给我的同事 Peyton
see what he can do with this in
让大家来看一下 他能够用我说的这些新改进
his app.
在他的 App 里做些什么 谢谢
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jason.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Jason
So I'm working on an app for
我正在忙于一个
mountain climbers training for
为登山者们的下一次登山
their next summit.
进行训练的 App
I've got a HealthKit powered
我已经得到一个
view of all my users walking,
包括我的所有用户走路 徒步旅行和
hiking and stairclimbing
爬楼梯训练的
workouts.
HealthKit 动力视图
Now after extensive market
现在 经过广泛的市场调查
research, I've determined that
我已经确定了
mountain climbers travel to
那些去登山的登山者们
mountains and travelers should
是去山上旅行
know their vaccination status.
而旅行者应该知道他们的疫苗接种状态
So by the transitive property of
因此 通过未来发展的
future development mountain
传递特性
climbers should know their
登山者们应该知道
vaccination status.
他们的疫苗接种状态
So I'm going to help out my
所以 我将帮助我的用户们
I've started implementing a new
我已经开始进行一项新的实验
tab, an immunization dashboard.
一个免疫仪表板
So let me tap on what I have
所以 请允许我
now.
点击一下这个
Here's my immunization dashboard
这是我的免疫仪表板
and to start out with I'm going
首先我将
to display my users a list of
为我的用户展示
their current vaccinations and
他们目前的疫苗接种
I'm going to use the
并且我将用这个
HKClinicalRecords display name
HKClinicalRecords 来显示名称属性
I've already added the Health
我已经在我的项目中
Records capability to my project
添加了健康记录功能
and I've created a purpose
并且我已经创建了一个目标字符串
string to tell my users how I
来告诉我的用户们我要如何
plan to use their immunizations.
使用他们的免疫接种记录
Now it's time to implement my
现在是时候来展示我的仪表板了
So here I am at the
所以现在 我正在
ImmunizationsViewController
ImmunizationsViewController 中
powering that tab.
使用这个面板
In HealthKit it's good practice
在 HealthKit 中
to request authorization every
每次你的用户进入要用到 HealthKit 的 App
time your user enters the part
的部分时都要请求权限
of your application using
是非常好的一个做法
So for this app viewWillAppear
所以对于这个 App 来说
is a great place.
ViewWillAppear 是个很棒的地方
Here I need to first specify
在这里 首先我需要说明
that I'm interested in
我对于免疫记录样本
immunization record samples.
很感兴趣
And next, call my Health Store's
接下来 调用我的
requestAuthorization method.
健康中心的 requestAuthorization 方法
In the callback I'm going to
在回调中 我将检查是否成功
check for success and handle
并且恰当地
errors appropriately.
去处理错误
Finally, once I'm unauthorized
最终 一旦我未经授权
I'm going to call this query for
我将去调用这个
immunizations method which I'll
我即将执行的
implement now.
查询免疫的方法
Here in query for immunizations
在这个免疫接种查询中
I'm going to create a sample
我将创建一个示例
query, I'm going to iterate over
我将去遍历所有的返回样本
all the return samples, and I'm
并且我将让
going to pass each sample's
每一个样本的显示名称
display name to my data source.
都通过我的数据源
So let's do that.
好了让我们开始吧
Here I've got my sample query
在这里 我已经得到了我的查询样本
and I'm using the humanization
并且我正在使用人类
record sample type.
样本记录类型
No predicate because I want all
不需要足够确定 因为我想要
of the users' immunizations and
所有用户的免疫接种
similarly no limit because I
并且同样没有限制因为
want to get all of my users'
我想要得到
immunizations.
所有用户的免疫接种
No sort descriptors, it doesn't
没有排序描述符
matter to me in what order these
这些样本以什么顺序返回
samples are returned.
对我来说没有关系
And with that I'm going to check
并且我要根据这来检查结果
for results and if not handle
和看是否存在
errors appropriately.
没有被合适处理的错误
Next, I'm going to iterate over
接下来 我要遍历一遍样本
the samples and I'll pass them
并且我将根据显示名称让
to my data source by display
这些样本
name.
通过我的数据源
With the names in my data source
有了我的数据源里的这些名称
it's time to head out to the
便是时候去主队列
main queue and call this reload
调用这个我之前写的
UI method that I wrote earlier.
重加载的 UI 方法了
Finally, I'm going to execute my
最后 我要在健康中心中
sample query on my Health Store
执行我的这个样本查找
and that's all it takes, so
以上就是整个过程
let's build and run.
现在让我们来建立并运行它吧
So here I have my training log,
所以 这是我的训练日志
I'm going to tap on my
我将要点击我的
immunization dashboard tab.
免疫仪表板选项
I see the new Health Records
我看到一个新的健康记录授权表
authorization sheet explaining
它向我的用户解释
to my users how my app could
我的 App 可能会如何
potentially use my users' health
使用用户的健康记录的
I'm going to tap continue and
我要点击继续
here my user has a chance to
然后在这里 我的用户可以
allow or deny categories as they
准许或拒绝
see fit.
他们觉得合适的类别
There is my purpose string that
这是我早些时候
I defined in my Info.plist
在我的 Info.plist 中
earlier alongside a link to my
伴随着一个我的 App 隐私政策的链接
app's privacy policy.
所定义的目标字符串
Now users have to explicitly
现在用户必须明确地
switch for every single
切换每一个单一类别
category, there's no turn on all
没有一个可以
button.
一次性打开所有类别的按钮
So for the purposes of the demo
所以 出于这次演示的目的
I'm going to enable
我打算启用免疫接种
immunizations and to have share
并且去分享现在的记录
For future records I'll leave
至于未来的记录
with the default Ask Before
我将把它设成默认为在分享前进行询问
Sharing and I'll tap done.
然后我点击完成
And just like that I have a list
然后 就像这样 我拥有了一个
of all my users' immunizations.
我所有用户的免疫接种清单
So that's just--
所以 这只是
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So that's just using display
所以这只是使用显示名称
name, but there's a lot more
但是还有很多信息
information contained in the
包含在拥有
clinical records FHIR resources.
临床记录的 FHIR 资源当中
So to tell you more about FHIR
所以 为了让你了解更多关于 FHIR 的信息
I'd like to hand it back to
我将把接下来的部分
Jason.
交还给 Jason
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Peyton.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Peyton
So Peyton just showed us how we
好了 Peyton 刚才给我们展示了
can request authorization in our
在我们的 App 中 我们如何去申请权限
app, query for data, and take
如何查找数据
advantage of the new display
以及如何在 HKClinicalRecord 上
name on HKClinicalRecord to
利用新的显示名称
present that information to
以用户们所熟悉的方法
users in a way they're familiar.
去显示信息
So now let's take a look at FHIR
所以 现在让我们来看看 FHIR
and see what you can do with
以及你能够用这种
this rich data format.
丰富的数据格式来做些什么
Users interact with multiple
用户在一生中会与多个
healthcare institutions over the
医疗保健机构进行交流
course of their lives and these
并且它们经常运用
are often running different
不同的电子健康记录系统
electronic health record systems
而这些系统
that don't always represent data
并不总是以同样的方式
in the same way.
来表示数据
This makes interoperability
这便使得交互操作性
incredibly difficult.
变得非常困难
So to address this the
所以为了解决这个问题
healthcare community came
医疗团体为了一个叫做
together in an effort called the
Argonaut 的项目
Argonaut Project, this uses
而聚集了起来
FHIR, a flexible JSON
这个项目利用 FHIR
representation of health records
一个灵活的表示健康记录的 JSON 表示
and [inaudible] 2 as defined by
并且 [ 音质不清晰 ]
the Smart Authorization Guide to
如智能授权指南中所定义的那样
allow connections, consistent
允许连接
connections to healthcare
与医疗机构保持持续性连接
institutions and to allow data
并且允许数据
to be downloaded in a common
在一个共同格式下
format and related across those
跨越多个相关的机构
multiple institutions.
被下载下来
FHIR itself models a huge
FHIR 本身模拟了
universe of health data from
从过敏不耐症到
allergy intolerance to vision
视觉处方的庞大的健康数据
prescription and it organizes
并且它将这些数据
this data into different data
组成不同的数据类型
types called resources.
我们把这些数据类型叫做资源
Each resource has a resource
每个资源都有一个资源类型
type and there is one for each
并且每个健康数据也
and every kind of health data.
都有一个资源类型
Today we are selecting the eight
如今 我们正在选择八个
most common resource types and
最常见的资源类型
these are defined within the
并且这些都是在
Argonaut Project and we are
Argonaut 项目中定义的
grouping these into the seven
我们将它们分成
different clinical types that we
我们之前看到的
saw earlier.
七种不同的临床类型
You'll note that we split
你会发现我们将
observations into lab results
得到的观测数据分成实验结果
and vital signs based on the
和基于分类的生命特征
categorization and we group
并且我们将
multiple medication resource
多种药物资源类型
types into the medications
归入药物类别
category.
因此 FHIR 将数据
JSON dictionary and there are
表示为一个 JSON 字典
some key properties that are
并且有一些关键属性
present on all FHIR resources.
会在所有的 FHIR 资源当中表现出来
Things like the resource type,
比如资源类型
here we're looking at an
在这里我们看到的是一个观测数据
observation and this tells us
并且它告诉我们
that in the context of health
在健康的情况下
this is a lab result or a vital
这是一个实验结果
sign.
还是一个生命特征
We also have an ID present on
我们也有一个代表
all resource types.
所有资源类型的 ID
This is a unique identifier for
这是一个属于这个资源的
that resource, but you should
独一无二的标识符
note that it is only unique
但是你应该注意它只是
within the domain of that
在这个医疗机构中的
resource type for that
这个资源类型里
healthcare institution.
是独一无二的
One of the most fundamental
FHIR 的最基本的一个
building blocks of FHIR is a
建筑模块就是编码
This allows for a reference to a
这允许我们对
unique identifier or a code
外部编码系统中的
scoped within an external coding
唯一标识符或者编码
system.
能有一个参考
There are a number of coding
有大量的在 FHIR 中
systems specified within FHIR
指定的编码系统
and you can use these to find
你可以用这些来
out more about the items that
找到更多在医学记录中
are referenced in medical
所涉及的
records or to relate specific
或是跨多个医疗机构
things across multiple
相关联的
healthcare institutions.
项目信息
Here we're actually looking at a
在这里 我们实际上是在看一个
category coding which tells us
类别编码
that this is a lab result.
它告诉我们 这是一个实验结果
There's also a code in the case
当然这里还有一个
of an observation for what is
针对于正在被测量的内容的代码
This is blood glucose as defined
这是在 LOINC 编码系统中
in the LOINC coding system and
定义的血糖
it could take that code and look
它能够使用这段代码
it up in the LOINC database for
并且在 LOINC 数据库中
alternative names and further
查找能够替代的名称
information.
和更多的信息
And of course this is an
当然了这是一个观测
observation so I have the value
所以我拥有
that is observed.
被观察到的值
This is 60 milligrams per
这是每分升 60 毫克
deciliter and you'll note that
并且你会注意到
even the units here are coded,
即使单位都被编码过了
so I have a really comprehensive
我对于正在发生的事情
on.
有一个非常全面的了解
FHIR resources have many
FHIR 资源有很多
additional data elements and I
额外的数据元素
encourage you to go and look at
并且我鼓励你们去看看
the Argonaut Project
Argonaut 项目的文档
documentation to find out more
来了解更多的信息
and I'll have details of these
我将在最后
at the end.
详细介绍这些
In HealthKit we model a FHIR
在 HealthKit 中我们建模了一个 FHIR 资源
resources as HKFHIRResource.
来作为 HKFHIRResource
We provide some key properties
我们提供了一些关键属性
like the data, access to the
比如数据和对于完整的
full raw data.
原始数据的访问通道
We surface common elements like
我们表示出像
the resource type and
资源类型和标识符
identifier.
这样的常见元素
You can access the data using
你可以利用可编码 Swift 或
Swift codable or JSON
JSON 序列化
serialization.
来访问这些数据
Here you can see that I've
在这里 你可以看到
defined my own codable struct,
我已经定义了我自己的可编码结构
my codable observation and I'm
我的可编码观测
using that to pull out the value
并且我正在用它来
quantity that we saw earlier.
寻找之前我们看到的量化值
You can have confidence that the
你可以认为
data is structured correctly
数据结构是正确的
here as we only share valid FHIR
因为我们只通过 API
resources through the API.
分享有效的 FHIR 资源
We also introduce some
我们也引进了一些
predicates to make it easier for
更为确定的信息 来使得你可以
you to work with
更好地操作
HKClinicalRecord.
HKClinicalRecord
We have a predicate to allow you
我们有一个允许你去
to query by resource type, here
按资源类型查找的推断
I'm looking for prescription or
在这里我在查找处方
in FHIR a medication order.
或者是 FHIR 的医疗订单
We also have a predicate to
我们同样也有一个
allow you to uniquely identify
允许你去通过其来源 资源类型
records by their source,
以及标识符
resource type and identifier.
来获得唯一标识记录的推断
This can be incredibly useful as
这会是非常有用的
FHIR resources can reference
因为 FHIR 资源能够
other FHIR resources.
参考其他的 FHIR 资源
For example, a medication might
例如 一个药物可能会
reference the condition that it
参考它要
treats.
治疗的情况
Now there are some additional
现在 这里有一些
considerations you need to be
当你去操作 FHIR 时你需要
aware of when working with FHIR.
知道的额外的事项
Firstly, FHIR resources may
首先 FHIR 资源可能
contain their own dates.
包含他们自己的日期
For example, prescriptions may
举个例子 处方中可能会
contain the order data of that
包含处方的订单数据
prescription while a condition
而身体状况中
may contain the onset date,
可能会包含开始日期
abatement date and the date that
消减日期以及
that prescription is first
首次检查时的处方日期
You should therefore use the
因此 你应该直接使用 FHIR 资源
FHIR resource directly to access
去为每一个
these dates for each resource
资源类型来
type.
访问这些日期
Start date and end date that are
在 HKSample 的超类中
available on the HKSample
可获得的开始日期和截止日期
superclass are set for the date
被设置为我们
that we first add that resource
第一次在 Health 中
to Health.
加入那个资源的日期
You should use source, resource,
当你去判断一个独一无二的
type and identifier when
健康记录时
uniquely identifying a health
你应该去使用源代码 资源
record.
类型和标识符
This will allow you to identify
这允许你在
a health record across the
医疗机构
course of its lifetime as it is
更新的过程中
updated by the healthcare
识别健康记录的整个生命周期
And finally, you should be aware
并且最终 你应该知道
that FHIR and JSON don't fully
就数值精确度而言
agree when it comes to numerical
FHIR 和 JSON
precision.
并不完全统一
FHIR ascribes significance to
FHIR 将小数点后面的
the number of digits following
数字的个数赋予了重要性
the decimal place and this can
并且当你使用可编码 Swift 或
be lost when using Swift codable
JSON 序列化时
or JSON serialization.
它可能会丢失
If it's really fundamental to
如果对于你的 App 来说
your app that you have full
这些信息
access to this information Swift
非常重要的话
codable and JSON serialization
那么可编码 Swift和 JSON 序列化
may not be appropriate tools.
或许并不是很合适的工具
And with that, I'd love to hand
就此而言 我很乐意让
back to Peyton and see what
Peyton 回来继续他的演讲
wonderful things he can do with
来让我们看一下通过这个新的 API
this new API.
他都能做些什么 [ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Jason.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Jason
So back to the immunization
那么回到之前我一直在从事的
dashboard I've been working on.
免疫接种仪表板上
I'm using HealthKit to fetch my
我正在使用 HealthKit 去获取
users' vaccinations, but right
我的用户的疫苗接种
now it's tough for a user to
但是现在 对于用户来讲
tell what vaccinations they have
他们很难知道 他们有什么疫苗接种
and what they might need to get.
以及他们可能会需要接种什么疫苗
So I'm going to solve that by
所以我将会通过
implementing an immunization
一个疫苗接种清单
checklist.
来解决这个问题
Users can see a summary of their
用户们可以看到用
immunizations in plain language.
通俗语言说明的 他们的疫苗简介
To populate this list I need to
要填充这个表的话 我需要知道的是
know that this combination
这个组合疫苗
vaccine induces immunity against
增加抵抗水痘和 MMR 的免疫力
Health institutions speak
卫生机构讲着不同的语言
different languages so I can't
所以我不能仅仅
rely on name alone, so that's
依赖于名字
where the interoperability of
所以 这就是 FHIR 的互操作性
FHIR comes into play.
所扮演的角色
FHIR gives a way to use
FHIR 提供了一种方式去
predefined codes rather than
使用预定义代码而不是
natural language to specify what
自然语言 来说明事物
So after taking a look at the
所以 在看过 FHIR 文件以后
FHIR documentation here's the
这便是我想到的
algorithm I've come up with to
能够用来
identify a chickenpox vaccine.
识别水痘疫苗的算法
First, I'll take the
首先 我将从 JSON 中
immunization records JSON, I'm
得到免疫记录
going to deserialize it and pull
我将把它反序列化
out the vaccination code in a
并在 CVX 系统中
system called CVX.
提取疫苗代码
CVX is a commonly used coding
CVX 是一种在免疫接种中
system for immunizations, but
常用的编码系统
there are many other coding
还有很多其他的
systems for different areas of
针对不同医学领域的编码系统
Finally, I'm going compare the
最后 我将把我在免疫接种记录中
CVX code I found in my
发现的 CVX 码和我所知道的
immunization record to a list of
能够增强对水痘的免疫力的
vaccines I know induce immunity
疫苗清单
against chickenpox.
进行比较
If there's a match I'll show a
如果它们互相匹配
checkmark in my UI next to
我会在我的 UI 中 水痘的旁边做一个标记
So let's talk about the
所以 接下来让我们来讨论一下
immunization record JSON.
免疫记录 JSON
The structure starts with a
这个结构以一个
resource type immunization.
资源类型免疫接种开始
There's a vaccine code object
这里有一个疫苗代码对象
and contained therein is an
包含一个数组的编码
There may be multiple codings,
也许会出现多个编码
so I need to search by system to
所以我需要去通过系统查找
find CVX.
来找到 CVX
In this example, the first
在这个例子中
system is NDC so I move until I
第一个系统是 NDC
see CVX.
所以我往下找直到看到 CVX
With that in hand I look at the
就这样我不断查找
code and I look it up and I see
然后我就会看见
that I have MMRV.
我有 MMRV
So that's the structure of these
这就是这些
immunization records JSON.
免疫记录 JSON 的结构
Now it's time to implement.
现在是时候来实践了
So here we are back in my
所以我们现在回到
immunizations view controller.
我的免疫视图控制器中
I've done some work ahead of
我已经提前完成了一些工作
time to implement the UI of the
来使用这个清单的 UI
checklist and I instantiate it
并且我用
with a showChecklist property.
showChecklist 属性实例化了它
Now it's time to populate my
那么现在 是时候来用数据
checklist with data.
来填充我的清单了
Here I am in the query for
现在我在这个
immunizations method.
免疫方法的查询中
When I iterate over my users'
当我对我的用户样本进行遍历时
samples I'm going to add a call
我将在一个叫做
to a new method
matchCodedVaccine 的新方法中
matchCodedVaccine and I'll pass
添加一个调用 并且如果
it if the sample is FHIR
遇到的样本是 FHIR 资源的话
resource, so let's implement
我将会通过它
that now.
好了现在让我们来实践吧
Here I am in matchCodedVaccine
在这里 我在资源中的 matchCodedVaccine
from resource and what I need to
并且我需要去做的是对这个 FHIR 资源数据
do is deserialize the FHIR
进行反序列化操作
resources data, pull out the
取出接种代码
vaccination codes, search for
查找 CVX
CVX, and compare it against
并且将它和
lists of CVX codes for different
不同疾病的 CVX 代码进行比较
I have a lot of freedom in how I
在如何选择反序列化 FHIR 资源上
choose to deserialize the FHIR
我有很大的自由
resource, so today I'm going to
所以今天 我将使用
use Swift codables.
可编码 Swift
I need to define a codable for
我需要为我
exactly the keys that I'm
真正感兴趣的关键字
interested in.
去定义一个可编码量
So I've done that now.
好了我已经操作完了
An immunization resource has a
每个免疫资源有一个疫苗代码
vaccine code, a vaccine code has
每个疫苗代码有一个
an array of codings and a
编码数组并且
vaccine coding has a system and
每个疫苗编码有一个
a code.
系统和一个代码
With that I instantiate a JSON
有了这些 我实例化一个 JSON 解码器
decoder and I use it to decode
并且用它来将一个
the FHIR resources data as an
FHIR 资源数据解码成一个
immunization resource.
免疫资源
All that's left is to iterate
剩下的就是去对每个编码进行遍历
over each coding, check to see
检查一下看是否
whether the system is CVX, and
这个系统是 CVX
then pass the code to this
然后将代码传递给此方法
method to mark it in the data
好把它标记在数据源中
All this method does is compares
这个方法的任务就是
the code against lists of codes
将代码和包含每个疾病的代码的清单
per disease and if there's a
相比较 然后
match marks in the UI that
如果在 UI 中发现了匹配标示
disease for the found disease.
说明它是我们已发现的疾病
So with that I'm going to build
所以 我要用它来建立
and run and take a look at my
来运行并查看
immunization checklist.
我的免疫清单
So here I am on my training log,
所以现在 我在我的训练日志中
I'm going to tap on the
我要去点击免疫接种键
that with a few lines of code I
就像这样 通过几行代码
have an immunization checklist.
我便拥有了一个免疫清单
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So that's an example of solving
这就是一个用 FHIR 来
a problem using FHIR.
解决问题的例子
Now for a word on granting
现在我将把时间
to hand it back to Jason.
留给 Jason
Jason.
Jason [ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Peyton.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Peyton
So Peyton has shown us how we
所以 Peyton 已经向我们展示了
can take that rich FHIR data and
我们该如何运用丰富的 FHIR 数据
take advantage of the coding
和如何合理地利用我们
that's provided to really
所提供的编码
provide our users with a very
这真的为我们的用户
meaningful and comprehensive
在他们的健康记录方面
experience around their health
提供了非常有意义的全面的使用
And now I'd like to think a
现在 让我们来想一想
little bit about how you can
在这个领域
help protect your users' privacy
你该如何保护你的用户的隐私
As you've seen this is
正如你所看到的一样
incredibly sensitive data.
这是一个令人难以置信的敏感数据
We've built privacy in from the
我们已经从头开始
ground up, establishing secure
建立了隐私
connections direct to healthcare
并与医疗机构
institutions.
建立了直接的安全连接
Downloading data straight to
能够直接从用户的
users' iOS devices.
iOS 设备上下载数据
Storing it securely in
把它安全地
HealthKit.
存储在 HealthKit 中
And providing comprehensive
并且围绕着这个
management tools around access
数据的访问端口
to that data.
提供了全面的管理工具
Your users will expect you to
你的用户们将期望你去
treat their data with that same
以同样的关心和关注程度
level of care and attention.
去对待他们的数据
Every choice that you make here
你在这里做的每一个选择
can have a direct impact on
都将直接影响到每个用户
This can be a truly positive
这可能是一个积极的影响
impact and it's why we are
并且这就是我们选择
choosing to provide this API
去提供这个 API 的原因
today, but it can also be a
但是 这个影响也可能是负面的
If users feel that this data is
如果用户觉得这个数据
out of their control or worse
不受他们的控制
still, it is shared without
或更糟的是
their consent.
数据会未经他们同意被分享出去
You can show respect for your
你可以对你的用户表现出尊重
users and help establish a
并且通过给他们
relationship of trust by
提供关于数据的清晰的政策
providing them with clear
去告诉他们
policies around that data and
你要用这个数据做什么
informing them what you do with
来建立一段可信的关系
This starts with your
从你的 App
application, your purpose
你的目标字符串
string, and your privacy policy
你的隐私政策开始
and it continues every step of
到你处理该数据时
the way as you work with that
的每一步
data and as you move it around.
都需要这种可信的关系
For example, you should make
举个例子 你应该确保
sure you give users details
你为你的用户提供了
about how you manage their data.
你是如何管理他们的数据的细节
You should publish clear
你应该发布清楚的
retention policies and you
保留政策 并且
should provide them tools to
你应该给他们提供工具
allow them to delete that data
去允许他们删除
should they choose to stop
他们不再想要与你分享的数据
And finally, you should make
最终 你应该确保
sure that you always request
你请求的数据
data proportional to your use
和你所要用到的是成正比的
You should never be asking for
你永远都不该去要求
more data than you need.
比你所需要的更多的数据
I encourage you all to go to the
我鼓励大家去看看
Privacy Talk, Better Apps
星期四下午 4 点的
Through Better Privacy on
隐私对话
Thursday at 4 p.m. and this
通过更好的隐私建立更好的 App
covers the whole ecosystem, so
它包含了整个生态系统
it's a great opportunity to find
所以这是个 去发现更多信息的好机会
So we've seen the new sample
所以 我们已经看到了我们
types that we're introducing to
早就介绍过的支持健康记录的
support Health Records.
新的样本类型
We understand how to configure
我们明白如何在我们的 App 中
in our app, to request
配置授权和隐私字符串
authorization and to query for
以请求权限和查找数据
Hopefully I have shown you just
希望我所展示的东西
enough to whet your appetite to
足以激起你的兴趣
go and find out more about FHIR.
去探索和发现更多关于 FHIR 的信息
And we've seen how you can do
并且我们已经看到了
more to help protect your users'
为了帮助用户们保护他们的隐私
privacy.
你还能做什么
We continue to be amazed by the
我们为我们的开发团队
fantastic apps that our
所创造的精彩的 App
developer community creates and
和当它访问用户的健康数据时
how it really empowers users
赋予用户
when accessing their health
真正的权力 而感到惊喜
This is a journey that we
这是一个我们基于健康
started with Health and
和 HealthKit 的探究
HealthKit and it's one that we
并且它也是
have continued with ResearchKit
我们对于 ResearchKit
and CareKit.
和 CareKit 的延续
And now today with Health
今天 伴随着健康记录
Records and HealthKit we are
和 HealthKit
thrilled to be continuing on
我们非常激动地
that journey with you.
跟大家一起探讨这些
We can't wait to see what
我们已经迫不及待地想知道
amazing things you do.
你们能够开发出什么
You can find the documentation
你可以从我身后的 URL 中
that I was talking about earlier
和我们拥有的一些实验室中
at the URL behind me and we have
找到我之前说过的文件
We have a health and fitness lab
在这次谈话以后
immediately after this talk
会有一个健康和健身实验室
where we're very happy to get
我们会在那里
you started with this new API.
与你一起体验这个新的 API
Our colleagues Anherika and
我们的同事 Anherika 和
Kareem have a talk tomorrow
Kareem 将在明天早上进行一个会谈
morning introducing new ways to
来介绍新的运动方式
And we have a health fitness and
并且我们明天
research get together tomorrow
还有一项关于健康健身的研究
night where it's an opportunity
那对你来说将是一个
for you all to get to know each
了解别人和与我们交流的好机会
so please do come along to that.
所以请你们明天一定不要错过
And with that, thank you very
对此 非常感谢大家
much and have a fantastic
希望大家有一个精彩的会议
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]